It is only right to apologize
when you are at fault.
You don't have to dwell on it, Mr. Yang.
I lived in Yizhou for over ten years.
I am used to it.
Mr. Yang,
if you truly regret your actions,
you should treat the Ji family
more favorably moving forward.
I'd better hurry back to dye the silk.
Wait a minute.
Since I'm here to apologize,
I must show some sincerity.
What is this?
There is nothing on it.
A gift from you?
What kind of dye did you use?
How could you tell I used dye?
Well, I wouldn't be bothered
if you showed me something else.
So, do you want a favor,
or do you want this instead?
Why are you so insincere?
If you're going to apologize,
then do it properly!
Why are you making her choose?
You're right, Linglong.
Mr. Jiang,
your wife just called you home for dinner.
Alas, don't rush me!
Good work takes time!
It's time for some flower cookies.
Ms. Ji,
my madam requested to meet you.
Your madam is…?
The daughter of General Niu, Ms. Niu.
I've never had any dealings
with your madam.
Why would she want to meet me?
My madam saw the velvet flowers
you presented at the Splendor Showcase,
and she adored them.
She is asking if you could replicate them
using the flowers she grows.
Can you… accept the order?
Well… I'll have to take a look
at the flowers first.
- After them!
- Yes, sir!
- What happened?
- As per your orders,
we had been scouting the cave for days.
Nothing happened at all.
But a group of people suddenly
showed up today and ambushed us.
THE NIU RESIDENCE
Ms. Niu, Ms. Ji has arrived.
Greetings, Ms. Niu.
Ms. Ji, it's good to see you again.
Please, sit.
I've actually wanted
to meet you for a long time.
I'm merely a commoner who happened
to cross paths with you once.
How did you come to know of me?
Falling flowers filled the sky
during the Splendor Showcase,
and Flushed Rose stunned the whole crowd.
Who in Yizhou hasn't heard of you?
Actually, Ms. Ji, I admire you greatly.
You admire me?
Ms. Niu, you come from
a distinguished background.
What's there to envy about me?
Ms. Ji, I want to be like you.
I want to build a career as a woman
and prove to my father
that a woman's future
is not only limited to marriage.
Ms. Niu, you certainly are ambitious.
I'm sure you will achieve
whatever you set your heart on.
What a fine tea.
Ms. Ji,
would you be interested in joining me
to oversee the brocade business in Yizhou?
I know that you and Mr. Zhao are in love,
but the Zhao family opposes it.
I can help you
secure your marriage with him…
And restore the Ji family's prestige
from your father's era.
Ms. Niu, with all
your wealth and influence,
why would you lower yourself
to pursue a career?
Merchants are considered
the lowest of society.
Ms. Niu, I truly find it hard
to believe your words.
Ms. Ji, you're a very cautious person.
Very well.
Let me show you why I want this.
- This is…?
- My mother.
My mother was only 16
when she married into this family
and bore five children for my father.
However, my father only desired a son
who could fight alongside him.
Sadly,
after five attempts,
all he had were daughters.
When I was born,
my mother's health deteriorated,
and she could no longer bear children.
She never left the house ever since.
General, when will you return?
Mrs. Niu…
She doesn't recognize me either.
General…
Now, she has become a woman
who only spends her days
waiting for her husband's return.
My father married off
all four of my sisters
to men who could help him gain more power.
I, too, have been married twice,
but I won't accept my fate.
Since women can't be officials,
I'll venture into business.
I'll show my father that
I'm better than any man he chooses for me.
Ms. Niu, you sure are ambitious.
I truly admire you.
Bloom Society and Flushed Rose
have proved your worth.
Join me,
and you can reach even greater heights.
Together, we can take full control
of Yizhou's brocade business.
Ms. Niu, you drive a tempting offer,
and I appreciate your honesty.
However, I believe that
personal feelings should
never be mixed with business.
My feelings for Mr. Zhao
cannot be used as a bargaining chip.
Besides, I founded Bloom Society
to give people like Ms. Zhu and myself,
who have no status or power,
a way forward.
If I were to join forces with you,
I would be no different from Mrs. Hua.
For that reason,
I must decline your offer.
As I have said,
Ms. Ji, you still don't grasp
what it is like to hold true power.
True power
is the ability to prevent you
from succeeding in anything
that goes against my will.
FLUSHED ROSE
JI YINGYING FROM YIZHOU'S SANDAOYAN
DYEHOUSE CREATED A NEW COLOR, FLUSHED ROSE
IS APPROVED FOR SALE BY THE OFFICER
OF THE WEAVING AND DYEING BUREAU
Shouldn't this registration document
be on its way to Chang'an?
No wonder Mrs. Hua insisted
I take on
the Flushed Rose orders that day.
Turns out there was
more to it than I thought.
Ms. Niu, you must be the rumored
benefactor behind the Hua family.
That doesn't matter.
The real question is,
will you reconsider your decision?
I have made up my mind.
Thank you for your kindness, Ms. Niu.
It's getting late. I'll take my leave now.
Ms. Ji, please wait.
What are you doing? Let go!
Let go of me!
Ms. Ji, I gave you a chance.
Ms. Niu, your actions right now
only prove that
I was right to reject your offer.
If you refuse to work with me,
then you'll serve me instead.
Ms. Ji, you can only leave this place
once you've dyed the Shu Red Silk.
Hold on.
It's too late for regrets.
Ms. Niu,
can I send a letter to my family
to let them know I'm safe?
I don't want to worry them.
Besides, I'm sure
you don't want this to escalate either.
I may come from a humble background,
but Mr. Sang is part of our Bloom Society.
Get her a pen and a paper.
Yes, madam.
Ms. Niu, she is done.
"Yaoting, Mother, I have learned that
a landslide has happened
300 li outside Yizhou
and delayed the delivery
of the registration document.
I have rented a carriage
to retrieve the document.
Time is tight.
I can't explain in detail.
Please forgive me.
Yaoting, Mother,
remember to buy more ingredients
for the flower cookies and the rest.
We need a lot to produce Flushed Red.
I didn't have enough money
when I bought the dye last time.
Thankfully, Ms. Yu lent me two guan.
Please repay her for me.
Yaoting, Mother, don't worry about me."
Deliver this to the Ji residence later.
Yes.
Keep an eye on her.
If she escapes,
you'll pay for it with your life.
Understood.
These are all materials
for dyeing Shu Red Silk.
Why are they all here?
Why aren't you working? Stop dawdling!
I'm watching you.
These ordinary ingredients won't do
if you want to dye Shu Red Silk.
Then, what else do you need?
I need eight liang of ashes
burned from redwoods,
one jin of madder from the rocks,
and three and a half jin of safflowers
filled with morning dew.
That should be all.
Don't think of playing tricks.
Hurry and get them prepared.
Can you shoulder the blame
if there's a delay in the dyeing process?
You!
Wait here.
Ms. Niu, can Ji Yingying
really dye Shu Red Silk?
If she can dye it, we'll use hers.
If not, we'll use our own.
Mrs. Hua is already ruined,
and Ji Yingying refuses to comply.
Plus, the mountains are unsafe lately.
Even if it's not Yang Jinglan,
someone else is surely targeting us.
The best way to hide a drop of water
is to place it in the sea.
A loom doesn't belong in the mountains,
but if it's placed in a brocade workshop,
no one will suspect a thing.
Ms. Niu,
there is a letter from the General.
You may leave.
Yes, Ms. Niu.
- Ms. Niu.
- Read it.
Summarize the important parts for me.
Okay.
THE SIXTH DAY OF YOU MONTH
IS HIS BIRTHDAY.
JIANXING AND I WENT TO MEET
YOUR POTENTIAL SUITOR. NIU JIN
The General is attempting
to marry you off again.
It's a distant relative
of the Right Military Commissioner.
He wishes to take you as his concubine.
General…
You're his daughter,
not a gift to be given away!
Quiet down.
This is the Niu residence,
not my home.
I just feel sorry for you, Ms. Niu.
The gentleman Ji Yingying fancies
is from the Zhao family,
the renowned brocade merchants in Yizhou.
The name is Zhao Xiuyuan, I believe?
I think so.
The Zhao family is the perfect sea
to hide the drop of water.
SAN HUA PAVILION
Young masters.
- Mister.
This way, please.
This might be a mistake.
Please pardon me.
You are at the right place.
I was the one who invited you, Mr. Zhao.
And you are?
My father is Niu Jin,
Vice Governor of Yizhou.
I am the fifth daughter in my family.
Surely you've heard of me.
Ms. Niu,
why did you invite me here?
Do you intend to keep standing there
to speak with me?
We're strangers.
For the sake of your honor,
it's best that I remain standing here.
Surely you know about my reputation.
Staying there isn't good for yours.
If there's nothing else,
I'll take my leave.
I'm a friend of Ms. Ji.
She asked me to deliver a message to you.
- Yu Yuan.
- Yes.
Mr. Zhao, please wait a moment.
Ms. Niu,
what business do you have with me?
When people see my face
and learn about my status,
they either fear me,
avoid me, or fawn over me.
But you're the only one
who remains unmoved.
Are you not afraid of me?
I don't judge people by their appearances,
only by their hearts.
Excuse me.
Don't you want to hear
the message Ms. Ji left for you?
No.
Yingying would never
entrust someone like you
to deliver a message to me.
What kind of person am I in your eyes?
Calculative and unpredictable.
Alright.
Let me bare my heart to you today.
I fell in love with you at first sight.
I wish for you to accept me.
Careful with what you say.
I am already engaged.
I'm afraid I cannot reciprocate
your affections.
- Is it Ms. Ji from Huanhua Dyehouse?
- Please don't come any closer.
But I have heard that
the Zhao family has already
annulled the engagement.
Even so, I only wish
to marry Yingying in this life.
Please don't make it difficult for me.
Mr. Zhao,
do you realize the weight of my words?
I am the daughter of Niu Jin.
There is nothing
I cannot achieve in Yizhou.
Everyone knows the power of General Niu.
But I truly seek nothing.
If there's nothing else today,
then thank you for the hospitality.
I'll take my leave.
Ms. Niu, Mr. Zhao Senior
will soon hear about you
reserving the entire San Hua Pavilion
just to meet Mr. Zhao.
But will the Zhao family
really take action?
Mr. Zhao Senior is a wise man.
He will understand.
But Ms. Niu,
is Mr. Zhao really
the one you want to choose?
You think he is unsuitable?
He remained unfazed even after
learning about my identity.
He showed neither shock nor disdain
upon seeing my face.
Just for that alone,
he stands above the rest.
But his heart
already belongs to Ji Yingying.
He will never truly love you.
Love?
Do you think I need something like that?
Rather than letting my father marry me off
to some random household,
I'd rather act first.
The Zhao family is one I can control,
and one I urgently need to control.
The Zhao family
is the perfect place
to hide that drop of water.
With the Zhao family's brocade workshop,
I won't need to exhaust myself
weaving brocade in the mountains.
Ji Yingying, since you won't submit to me,
I will just take what you hold dear.
I wonder if Yaoting
has received my letter.
I asked Ms. Yu about it.
She said dyeing Shu Red Silk
doesn't require the things you mentioned.
Are you playing me as a fool?
I'm the one dyeing the silk.
What would she know?
How dare you talk back?
I'm going to teach you a lesson!
Let me teach you a lesson!
You! Still running?
How dare you talk back?
Let's see where you can run.
You!
Why aren't you running?
I'm telling you.
This is just a warning.
If you dare mess with me again,
you won't live to regret it.
Keep an eye on her.
THE ZHAO RESIDENCE
Grandfather.
I heard
Ms. Niu has taken a liking to you.
Grandfather, you must be mistaken.
I only met her briefly by chance.
How could there be any interest?
Is it her disinterest or yours?
You slighted Ms. Niu today.
Did you consider
if she bears a grudge,
Zhao Brocade won't stand a chance
against the Brocade Master?
Grandfather,
Yingying and I are in love.
I cannot accept Ms. Niu's favor.
Foolish boy!
I approved your marriage with Ji Yingying
because of Bloom Society and Flushed Rose.
Your union with her
will help our family greatly.
Xiuyuan,
but if you marry Ms. Niu…
I won't.
How dare you!
A messenger has been sent
to the Niu residence to propose marriage.
Ridiculous!
Grandfather,
she wouldn't want to marry a cripple.
My heart will not change.
Then you'll kneel here
until you have thought it through.
I will kneel.
- I…
- Mr. Zhao Senior!
Here's a message from the Niu residence.
They are inviting Mr. Zhao to visit.
Tell Ms. Niu that
Mr. Zhao will be there.
Yes, sir.
THE NIU RESIDENCE
You look rather worn, Mr. Zhao.
All thanks to you, Ms. Niu.
I have done nothing at all.
It was the Zhao family who came
to my family seeking a marriage proposal.
The Niu family wields tremendous power.
We met at San Hua Pavilion yesterday.
Did you plan all of this in advance?
Please.
Even if you dislike the idea,
you do not show it.
Your composure is admirable, Mr. Zhao.
Earlier, you asked me
if this was intentional.
I pity my sincerity.
You speak of it so disdainfully.
Let's be candid.
You are willing to lower yourself
to marry me, the son of a merchant.
What is your true intention?
Once we are married,
there are certain things
I will share with you.
Who would have thought
you are so desperate
to marry yourself off, Ms. Niu?
How dare you!
Do you know
how I got this scar on my face?
Everyone says I am cursed,
a bringer of bad luck to my husbands.
But in truth,
I wanted them dead.
And so, they died.
This scar was my father's lesson to me.
He was furious at the time,
and his hand slipped.
But I am grateful for this scar.
It earned me the opportunity
to hold power and make decisions.
Power once forced its will upon you.
Now you use it to force
your will on others.
That is the beauty of power.
YUEBUHUAN
Yuniang?
- Yuniang!
- Are you looking for me?
It is Yingying who sent me.
She said when
she bought dye the last time,
she borrowed two guan
but forgot to repay you.
I… I have only managed to earn one guan.
Two guan?
If I am ever in trouble,
I will send you a signal, Yu.
If I say,
I will repay one guan, come and save me.
If I say, I will repay two guan,
bring Mr. Yang with you.
- When did she ask you to come here?
- Yesterday.
Why did you not come yesterday?
I… I was busy collecting the money.
Where is she?
The letter said she went to investigate
the registration document.
A letter? You have not seen her in person?
- Where is the letter?
- The letter?
What had happened, Ms. Yu?
Wait for me outside.
FROM YINGYING
Why should I save you?
Mr. Yang, you love the people
like they are your children.
I do not acknowledge
a rebellious child like you.
If I am in such dire trouble
that I need both of you to save me,
then anything you wanted to know before,
you may ask, and I will answer.
Even if I want to save you,
I need to know where you are.
We have this.
FROM YINGYING
What exactly happened?
Nothing. You should go home.
But Yingying only left
a letter and disappeared.
I am worried about her.
Maybe I should hire a carriage
and go find her.
I will go find her.
You stay home and wait.
No, I will go.
Go home and wait! Trust me.
Alright.
I invited you here today
to enjoy a play with me.
Perhaps after watching,
you will reconsider your decisions.
Ms. Niu said to give you
half an hour to escape.
What kind of new torment is this?
It is a chance to live.
It all depends
on whether you want it or not.
Yingying!
What are you trying to do?
Just inviting you to watch a play.
Best stay away from the windows, Mr. Zhao.
These archers cannot hear sudden noises.
Otherwise, they might shoot at Ms. Ji.
- Ms. Niu!
- Do not move!
Do you believe I will kill you?
A cornered beast fights hardest.
Do you not find it entertaining?
Ms. Ji, your time is running out.
Will you continue?
I really will kill you!
Can you face the consequences
after killing me?
Can the Ji and Zhao families
bear the consequences?
I am sorry.
I will release you once I am outside.
Let me go…!
Do you hear that?
Release her!
What a match made in heaven.
Even your escape plans are identical.
Let me go!
Are you insane?
Mr. Zhao, you clearly
have never killled anyone.
Do you want to kill me?
Should I have them kill a few more
to teach you how it is done?
What exactly are you trying to do?
I have already told you.
From the moment I saw you,
I was captivated.
I wish for us to get married.
I hope you will grant my wish.
MARRIAGE AGREEMENT
Will you release Yingying
if I agree to this?
That depends on whether you are willing
to treat me sincerely
in the future, Mr. Zhao.
How insolent! You dare
cause trouble at the Niu residence!
Hand Yingying over immediately!
Ms. Niu,
there is an urgent decree from the palace.
They want Shu Red Silk.
I have already reported to the governor.
I must take Ji Yingying, the daughter
of the Red Silk Brocade Master,
to assist with the investigation.
Ms. Niu, surrender her at once.
Mr. Yang, you are quite the strategist.
You are not to be underestimated.
But I think you misunderstand, Mr. Yang.
Ms. Ji did visit my residence,
but she has since departed.
Whether she is here or not,
I will know after I search.
The General's residence
is not a place you can search at will.
The emperor's order cannot be defied.
Ms. Niu,
do you intend to resist
an imperial decree?
If you fail to find her,
the crime of forcibly entering
this residence
will not be easily excused.
Fine.
Forgive the intrusion.
- Search everywhere!
- Yes, sir!
Mr. Yang, no sign of her
on the eastern side.
Mr. Yang,
she is not in the backyard either.
- Keep searching!
- Yes, sir.
How dare you act on your own?
ERUDITE AND RESOLUTE IN PURPOSE
Did I not instruct you
to escort Ms. Ji safely back to her house?
How could you do something so foolish?
Please forgive me, miss.
I saw Ms. Ji
behaving arrogantly and rudely,
and I felt indignant.
That is why, in a moment of folly,
I made such a grave mistake.
Please spare me, miss.
Do you realize
if today's event were to spread,
and Ms. Ji's reputation were ruined,
even death would not atone
for your actions?
Enough, Ms. Niu.
This act of pity has gone far enough.
I will not speak of today's event.
Our paths will cross again in the future.